linkedin.com/in/ckcasil github.com/ccasil cesarkylecasil.me

### Summary

Cesar Kyle Casil is a Computer Science major from the University of California, Santa Cruz. He is currently practicing full stack web development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.js); he has experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. Since coming from both an accredited university and a coding bootcamp, he has not only acquired a unique set of skills, but has learned the importance of how they lead to success within the tech industry. His primary goal is to contribute his passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on his technical skills.

## Education

### University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

• Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

**Technical** Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, Python, C, LATEX Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response  $\mathbf{MySQL}, \mathbf{SQLite}, \mathbf{PostgreSQL}, \mathbf{MongoDB}, \mathbf{Mongoose.js}, \mathbf{Django}$  $\underline{\mathbf{D}}$ atabase:

ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks and Libraries: Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask <u>D</u>evelopment Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

(EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM) Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Struc-

tures, Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model

View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

#### Experience

VeEX Inc., Web Development Engineer, Santa Clara, CA

Apr 2019–Present

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Jan 2018–Jan 2019

- Built full-stack, modern, responsive web applications while providing quick feedback and sup-
- Lead a small team in collaboration with clients in order to create websites from the ground up

### MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- $\bullet$  Collaborated in a small team to present a road show plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

## Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Translated UI mockups into a working, interactive Android application using Android Studio and Java during its early stages
- Designed and created a functional implementation of the mobile applications interface
- Testing and quality assurance

# **Projects**

## Alex the Party

Miscellaneous:

Ongoing

E-commerce website selling photo prints. Takes customer from store front to cart to checkout.

• Technologies Used: Angular, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Bcrypt, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AWS (EC2), Responsive Wed Design (RWD)

## Megumi Hiramoto

Sept 2018–Dec 2018

Portfolio for Academy of Art student to display her studies in Fashion Journalism.

 $\bullet$  Technologies Used: React, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Wed Design (RWD)

# Love Changing the World, Inc.

Jun 2018-Oct 2018

Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding.

• Technologies Used: React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API

Gym Log Apr 2018

Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

## Dojo Attendance Tracker

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Baskin Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.

• Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)